<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A particular relation of the surrender of Galloway. Published by authority. From the camp before Galloway, July 22. 1691.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B27879</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99886013</idno>
  <idno type="VID">188618</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248535070</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing P606</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 816.m.17[80]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R225288</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99886013</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99886013e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B27879)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 188618)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C11:2[75])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A particular relation of the surrender of Galloway. Published by authority. From the camp before Galloway, July 22. 1691.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Edw. Jones in the Savoy,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1691.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="geographic_name">Ireland --  History --  War of 1689-1691 --  Campaigns --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Galloway (Galloway, Ireland) --  History --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="account">
            <pb facs="tcp:188618:1"/>
            <head>A Particular RELATION OF THE Surrender of Galloway.</head>
            <head type="sub">Published by Authority.</head>
            <opener>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>From the Camp before</hi> Galloway, <date>July 22. 1691.</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <p>ON Sunday the 19th Instant the Army marched from <hi>Atheuree</hi> to this place. The General immediately sent a Trumpeter to my Lord <hi>Dillon,</hi> Governor of the Town, and offered him the Benefit of the Lords-Justices procla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation of the 7th, which he inclosed to him, if he would surrender it before he was obliged to Fire his Cannon. The Answer was, <hi>That Monsieur</hi> Dussone, <hi>who Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded, was of the same Opinion with himself, and the rest of the Officers, who were re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>solved to defend it to the last.</hi> While it was Light, our Men made but small Advances, but at Night they Attack'd a small Fort they had made to Command a Valley be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween the Town and us, and immediately Beat the Irish out of it; And hearing that <hi>Baldarock O-Donnel</hi> intended to throw himself and his Brigade into the Place that Night or the next Morning, the Tin Boats were immediately put into the Water, and Six Regiments of Foot, and Four Squadrons of Horse and Dragoons, sent over the River, and posted in the way <hi>Baldarock</hi> was to take; so that finding no Succors could be put in on that side, he retired with his Rabble into the County of <hi>Mayo,</hi> burn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and destroying all the Country as he marched. The taking this Fort, and pas<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sing the Water, so suddenly, we suppose, were the things that frighted them into a Treaty; for on the 20th, about Ten in the Morning, the Governor desired a Safe-Conduct for some Persons he intended to send to the General to Capitulate, and in the Afternoon 3 of their Lieutenant-Colonels came out, and as many of ours went into the Town as Hostages. The Treaty lasted the rest of the day and night, they being often obliged to go back to Consult their Principals. At last it was agreed; <hi>That on next Sunday morning at Six a Clock, the Town should be delivered to such Officers as the General should appoint, and in the mean time we should have Five Hostages for the due Performance of Articles, whereof my Lord</hi> Clanriccard <hi>is one, and all the Outworks of the Town put into our Hands; That the Enemy should forbear to fortifie in this time, and withdraw all their Cannon from the Walls, but that we may be permitted to work and Post our selves where we will, provided we came not within</hi> 3 <hi>yards of the Wall, nor place any Cannon upon the Batteries we make. The Garison and Townsmen that remain have the Benefit of the Lords Justices Proclamation, which gives them their Estates and Liberties; And those who have a mind to depart, are to be Conducted safe to</hi> Limerick, <hi>with their Arms, Drums Beating,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>and Six Pieces of Cannon. They have Liberty to send to my Lord</hi> Tyr<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>connel, <hi>to acquaint him with what they have done, and invite him to do the same at</hi> Limerick. A French Vessel of 30 Guns sail'd out of the Harbour as we march'd hither, and two more remain still here.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed by <hi>Edw. Jones</hi> in the <hi>Savoy,</hi> 1691.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>